Lived any good books lately?
In the Mouth of Madness is a horror, mystery film directed by John Carpenter.
An insurance investigator visits a small town while looking into the
strange disappearance of a popular horror novelist.
He soon finds that the impact of the author’s
books is far more than inspirational.
John Trent, played by Sam Neill.
Linda Styles, played by Julie Carmen.
Sutter Cane, played by Jürgen Prochnow.
Dr. Wrenn, played by David Warner.
Saperstein, played by John Glover.
Robinson, played by Bernie Casey.
In the Mouth of Madness is a 1994 American supernatural horror film directed
and scored by John Carpenter and written by Michael De Luca.
It stars Sam Neill, Julie Carmen, Jürgen Prochnow,
David Warner and Charlton Heston.
Neill stars as John Trent, an insurance investigator who visits a small town while looking into the disappearance of a successful
author of horror novels, and begins to question his sanity as the lines between reality and fiction seem to blur.
Informally, the film is the third and final installment in what Carpenter refers to as his
"Apocalypse Trilogy", preceded by The Thing (1982) and Prince of Darkness (1987).
In the Mouth of Madness pays tribute to the works of author H.
Lovecraft in its exploration of insanity, and its title is derived
from the Lovecraft novella At the Mountains of Madness.
Distributed by New Line Cinema, In the Mouth of Madness received mixed
reviews upon release, but has gained a cult following.
The film explores themes of small town, insanity,
paranoia, diner, new hampshire.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and mind_bending.